<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on TAPAAL</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on TAPAAL</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Features</title><link>/features/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/features/</guid><description>Details about TAPAAL The TAPAAL tool provides:
a graphical GUI for drawing P/T nets (with PNML import/export) and extended timed-arc Petri nets, a simulator, a timed workflow net analyzer, stand-alone efficient verifiers, and a translation module using the UPPAAL engine at the back end. The standard model of timed-arc Petri nets is extended with:
component-based design, age invariants, urgent transitions, transport arcs, and inhibitor arcs. This extended model offers more expressive power than the standard timed-arc Petri net model [1,2,8] and such extensions are very convenient for modelling purposes.</description></item><item><title>Screenshots</title><link>/screenshots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/screenshots/</guid><description>Screenshots Click on the pictures to see large version.
Editor The main editor window of TAPAAL.
Verification The improved query designer makes it super easy to create queries without a detailed knowledge of the concrete syntax. Queries can be by expert users edited also manually.
TAPAAL provides a standalone verification engines as well as verification via a translation to UPPAAL timed automata. The integrating within the TAPAAL GUI is seemless the answers are displayed directly in TAPAAL.</description></item><item><title>Documentation</title><link>/documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/documentation/</guid><description>User Documentation For new users starting with TAPAAL, we recommend to run TAPAAL and open the following net intro-example.xml (the net can be open from files - Examples Nets - intro-example) which will explain the main modeling features and verification possibilites. After that you are welcome to solve the following TAPAAL exercises.
User Manual A user manual for TAPAAL is freely available on leanpub.
TAPAAL User Manual (to be updated with the newest features of TAPAAL 2.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>Contact Information To contact the development team, send an email to tapaal(at)cs.aau.dk
Development Team GUI and Translations: Jacob Hjort Bundgaard Jakob Dyhr Peter G. Jensen Mads Johannsen Kenneth Yrke Joergensen Jiri Srba Mathias G. Soerensen Jakob H. Taankvist Peter H. Taankvist Past contributors: Mathias Andersen Sine Viesmose Birch Joakim Byg Louise Foshammer Lasse Jacobsen Morten Jacobsen Thomas Stig Jacobsen Jacob Jon Jensen Mikael H. Moeller Christoffer Moesgaard Malte Neve-Graesboell Niels N.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.6.0. Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.6.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 15:14:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.6.0/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.6.0.
TAPAAL 3.6.0 is a new release that introduces:
Automatic layout generator for a net (available in Tools) Alignment of a net to the current grid size (available in View) Numerous bug fixes</description></item><item><title>Changelog</title><link>/download/changelog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/download/changelog/</guid><description>Changelog 3.6.0 (2019-10-21):
Automatic layout generator for a net (available in Tools) Alignment of a net to the current grid size (available in View) Numerous bug fixes 3.5.1 (2019-04-23):
Bugfixes 3.5.0 (2019-03-18):
Intervals on arcs can now be moved and placed arbitrarily TAPAAL model files now end with .tapn Removal of multiple places at the same time Soundness check in batch processing Easier sharing of places/transitions across components Improved export to tikz GUI refactoring and numerous bug fixes 3.</description></item><item><title>Older releases</title><link>/download/older-releases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/download/older-releases/</guid><description>Older releases TAPAAL 3.5.1 for Windows Download (64 bit)TAPAAL 3.5.1 for Linux Download (64 bit)
TAPAAL 3.5.1 for Mac Download (64 bit)TAPAAL 3.5.0 for Windows Download (64 bit)TAPAAL 3.5.0 for Linux Download (64 bit)
TAPAAL 3.5.0 for Mac Download (64 bit)TAPAAL 3.4.3 for Windows Download (64 bit)TAPAAL 3.4.3 for Linux Download (64 bit)
TAPAAL 3.4.3 for Mac Download (64 bit)TAPAAL 3.4.2 for Windows Download (64 bit)TAPAAL 3.4.2 for Linux Download (64 bit)TAPAAL 3.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL won 4 gold medals at MCC&#39;19</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.5.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 16:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.5.1/</guid><description>We are very happy to announce that at this year Model Checking Contest, our tool TAPAAL won four gold medals in the categories: reachability, CTL model checking, deadlock analysis and computation of upper-bounds. The detailed results can be found here: https://mcc.lip6.fr/results.php</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL won 4 gold medals at MCC&#39;19</title><link>/news/mmc19-4-gold-medals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 16:53:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/mmc19-4-gold-medals/</guid><description>We are very happy to announce that at this year Model Checking Contest, our tool TAPAAL won four gold medals in the categories: reachability, CTL model checking, deadlock analysis and computation of upper-bounds. The detailed results can be found here: https://mcc.lip6.fr/results.php</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.5.0</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.5.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 14:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.5.0/</guid><description>We are glad to announce a new version of TAPAAL 3.5.0 with the following updates.
Intervals on arcs can now be moved and placed arbitrarily TAPAAL model files now end with .tapn Removal of multiple places at the same time Soundness check in batch processing Easier sharing of places/transitions accross components Improved export to tikz GUI refactoring and numerous bug fixes This is a recommend update for all TAPAAL users.</description></item></channel></rss>