<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on TAPAAL</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on TAPAAL</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Features</title><link>/features/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/features/</guid><description>Details about TAPAAL The TAPAAL tool provides:
a graphical GUI for drawing P/T nets (with PNML import/export) and extended timed-arc Petri nets, a simulator, a timed workflow net analyzer, extension to game setting, stand-alone efficient verifiers, and a translation module using the UPPAAL engine at the back end. The standard model of timed-arc Petri nets is extended with:
component-based design, age invariants, urgent transitions, transport arcs, and inhibitor arcs.</description></item><item><title>Screenshots</title><link>/screenshots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/screenshots/</guid><description>Screenshots Click on the pictures to see large version.
Editor The main editor window of TAPAAL.
Verification The improved query designer makes it super easy to create queries without a detailed knowledge of the concrete syntax. Queries can be by expert users edited also manually.
TAPAAL provides a standalone verification engines as well as verification via a translation to UPPAAL timed automata. The integrating within the TAPAAL GUI is seemless the answers are displayed directly in TAPAAL.</description></item><item><title>Documentation</title><link>/documentation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/documentation/</guid><description>User Documentation For new users starting with TAPAAL, we recommend to run TAPAAL and open the following net intro-example.tapn (the net can be open from files - Examples Nets - intro-example) which will explain the main modeling features and verification possibilites. After that you are welcome to solve the following TAPAAL exercises.
User Manual We currently do not have an up-to-date user manual and are in the progress of creating a new documentation website.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>Contact Information To contact the development team, send an email to tapaal@cs.aau.dk
Development Team Current Core Team Tanguy Dubois Peter G. Jensen Kenneth Yrke Joergensen Jiri Srba Mikkel Tygesen GUI and Translations: Mathias Andersen Sine Viesmose Birch Jacob Hjort Bundgaard Joakim Byg Malo Dautry Tanguy Dubois Jakob Dyhr Louise Foshammer Lasse Jacobsen Morten Jacobsen Thomas Stig Jacobsen Jacob Jon Jensen Mads Johannsen Mikael H. Moeller Christoffer Moesgaard Malte Neve-Graesboell Kristian Morsing Pedersen Thomas Pedersen Lena Said Niels N.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 4.0.1</title><link>/news/tapaal-4.0.1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 09:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-4.0.1/</guid><description>We are happy to announce a new release of TAPAAL 4.0.1 that contains
Minor GUI fixes (loading of files, redo/undo, name genertion and version check) All users are encouradged to update to this version (including the previous alpha and beta releases of TAPAAL 4.0.0).</description></item><item><title>Best paper award at PN&#39;25</title><link>/news/pn25-best-paper-award/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 08:52:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/pn25-best-paper-award/</guid><description>We are very glad that our SMC engine for statistical model checking of stochastic timed-arc Petri nets received the best paper award at the 46th International Conference on Application and Theory of Petri Nets and Concurrency (Petri Nets 2025).
The paper can be obtained from https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-031-94634-9_9</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL Defends Three Gold Medals at MCC&#39;25</title><link>/news/mcc25-three-gold-medals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 08:52:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/mcc25-three-gold-medals/</guid><description>We are very happy to announce that at this year Model Checking Contest, our tool TAPAAL defended the gold medals in the Reachability, LTL and CTL categories. Moreover, we also received the 100% confidence badge, first time ever since the pariticpation of TAPAAL in MCC. We thank to all developers who contributed to the success of our tool at this year competition. The detailed results can be found here: https://mcc.lip6.fr/results.php.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 4.0.0</title><link>/news/tapaal-4.0.0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 09:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-4.0.0/</guid><description>We are happy to announce a majour new release of TAPAAL 4.0.0 that contains
Support for colored net editing, verification and unfolding/simulation Support for stochastic timed-arc Petri nets and statistical model checking (SMC) Support for verification of LTL and HyperLTL queries New search feature for locating places/transitions by their names, also in the query dialog Redisigned batch processing dialog and support for passing engine options directly in the command line Numerous GUI improvements (e.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL gets back 3 gold medals at MCC&#39;24</title><link>/news/mcc24-three-gold-medals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 08:52:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/mcc24-three-gold-medals/</guid><description>We are very happy to announce that at this year Model Checking Contest, our tool TAPAAL defended the gold medal in the CTL category and more over took back two additional gold medals in the LTL category as well as the most prestigius reachability category. Moreover, we also won two silver medals in upper-bounds and in global properties. We thank to all developers who contributed to the success of our tool at this year competition.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL wins a gold medal at MCC&#39;23</title><link>/news/mcc23-one-gold-medal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 08:52:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/mcc23-one-gold-medal/</guid><description>We are very happy to announce that at this year Model Checking Contest, our tool TAPAAL won a gold medal in the CTL model checking] category and was awareded four silver medals in the other categories (except for state-space exploration where we do not participate). The detailed results can be found here: https://mcc.lip6.fr/2023/results.php.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.9.5</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.9.5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 09:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.9.5/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.9.5 that contains
a bug fix for zooming when changing tabs fixes issues with boundeness check and with running some of the example nets, and distributed an updated verifytapn (continuous time) verification engine.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.9.4</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.9.4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 09:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.9.4/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.9.4 that contains
a bug fix for conclusive/inconclusive reporting verification answers for CTL and LTL model checking, and an updated untimed engine verifypn which fixes the reporting of verification statistics.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.9.3</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.9.3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 09:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.9.3/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.9.3 that contains
numerous bug fixes including passing of inclusion places to the continuous engine, fixes to the query dialog, copying of elements with environmental transitions, remebering of the last open file location, trace generation for LTL queries. an updated untimed engine verifypn which fixes trace generation issues when structural reduction rules are applied.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL won 3 gold medals at MCC&#39;22</title><link>/news/mcc22-three-gold-medals/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 08:52:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/mcc22-three-gold-medals/</guid><description>We are very happy to announce that at this year Model Checking Contest, our tool TAPAAL won three gold medals in CTL and LTL model checking and we regained the gold medal also in the reachability category this year. Moreover, we won two silver medals in upper-bounds and in global properties. The detailed results can be found here: https://mcc.lip6.fr/results.php.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.9.2</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.9.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 20:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.9.2/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.9.2 that contains
numerous bug fixes in transition highlighting, simulator and over/under-approximation.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.9.1</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.9.1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 20:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.9.1/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.9.1 that contains
numerous bug fixes, improved export to tikz, rearranged example nets with a few new nets, and new versions of all three verification engines.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.9.0</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.9.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 08:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.9.0/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.9.0 that contains
an updated GUI that now allows to ask LTL queries untimed verifypn engine supporting partial order reduction for LTL and heuristic search.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.8.1</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.8.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 08:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.8.1/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.8.1 that contains
improved performance of untimed verifypn engine, and numberous bug fixes and smaller GUI improvements.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL won 2 gold medals at MCC&#39;21</title><link>/news/mcc21-two-gold-medals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 08:52:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/mcc21-two-gold-medals/</guid><description>We are very happy to announce that at this year Model Checking Contest, our tool TAPAAL won two gold medals in CTL and LTL model checking, two silver medals in upper-bounds and reachability and one bronz medal in global properties. We are particularly pround of the gold medal in the LTL model checking as this was the first time TAPAAL participated in this category.The detailed results can be found here: https://mcc.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.8.0</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.8.0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 12:00:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.8.0/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.8.0 that contains
improved performance of untimed verifypn engine, the GUI can now show reduced net in the editor, and numberous bug fixes and smaller GUI improvements.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.7.1</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.7.1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 15:21:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.7.1/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.7.1 that contains larger refactoring and new features, in particular:
GUI and engine support for Petri net games (untimed and dicrete time), the possibility to explicitly edit timed/untimed and game/non-game nets, updated verifypn (untimed) engine, quick drawing of nets when holding ctrl while in arc-drawing mode, large refactoring and bug fixes in the GUI.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL won 2 gold medals at MCC&#39;20</title><link>/news/mcc20-two-gold-medals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 10:53:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/mcc20-two-gold-medals/</guid><description>We are very happy to announce that at this year Model Checking Contest, our tool TAPAAL won two gold medals in global properties and CTL model checking, one silver medal in upper-bounds and bronz medal in reachability. The detailed results can be found here: https://mcc.lip6.fr/results.php or in the press release https://www.cs.aau.dk/news-and-events/show/aau-tool-remains-among-the-best-model-checking-tools-in-the-world.cid474672.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.6.1</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.6.1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 15:21:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.6.1/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.6.1 that contains numerous bug fixes and improvements, in particular:
highlighted constants in editor now blink save and load paths are not remembered separately fixed integration with UPPAAL verifyta engine loading of large nets is now twice as fast on linux you can start tapaal with a net as argument, on mac the icon is now dropable.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.6.0</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.6.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 15:14:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.6.0/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.6.0.
TAPAAL 3.6.0 is a new release that introduces:
Automatic layout generator for a net (available in Tools) Alignment of a net to the current grid size (available in View) Numerous bug fixes</description></item><item><title>Changelog</title><link>/download/changelog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/download/changelog/</guid><description>Changelog 4.0.1 (2025-08-07):
Minor fixes in TAPAAL GUI (opening files, redu/undo, generation of place tranistion/names and fixes to version check) 4.0.0 (2025-06-25):
Support for colored net editing, verification and unfolding/simulation Support for stochastic timed-arc Petri nets and statistical model checking (SMC) Support for verification of LTL and HyperLTL queries New search feature for locating places/transitions by their names, also in the query dialog Redisigned batch processing dialog and support for passing engine options directly in the command line Numerous GUI improvements (e.</description></item><item><title>Older releases</title><link>/download/older-releases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 14:45:55 +0200</pubDate><guid>/download/older-releases/</guid><description>Older releases TAPAAL 4.0.0 for Windows Download (64 bit) TAPAAL 4.0.0 for Linux Download (64 bit) TAPAAL 4.0.0 for Intel Mac Download (64 bit) TAPAAL 4.0.0 for Arm Mac Download (64 bit)
TAPAAL 3.9.5 for Windows Download (64 bit)
TAPAAL 3.9.5 for Linux Download (64 bit)
TAPAAL 3.9.5 for Mac Download (64 bit)
TAPAAL 3.9.4 for Windows Download (64 bit)
TAPAAL 3.9.4 for Linux Download (64 bit)</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.5.1</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.5.1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.5.1/</guid><description>We are glad to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.5.1.
TAPAAL 3.5.1 is a release that fixes numerous bugs in the GUI introduced in the 3.5.0 release and it also fixes trace generation issue in the untimed verifypn engine.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL won 4 gold medals at MCC&#39;19</title><link>/news/mmc19-4-gold-medals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 16:53:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/mmc19-4-gold-medals/</guid><description>We are very happy to announce that at this year Model Checking Contest, our tool TAPAAL won four gold medals in the categories: reachability, CTL model checking, deadlock analysis and computation of upper-bounds. The detailed results can be found here: https://mcc.lip6.fr/results.php</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.5.0</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.5.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 14:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.5.0/</guid><description>We are glad to announce a new version of TAPAAL 3.5.0 with the following updates.
Intervals on arcs can now be moved and placed arbitrarily TAPAAL model files now end with .tapn Removal of multiple places at the same time Soundness check in batch processing Easier sharing of places/transitions accross components Improved export to tikz GUI refactoring and numerous bug fixes This is a recommend update for all TAPAAL users.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL solved all CTL queries at RERS Competition</title><link>/news/tappal-rerscompetition2018/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 15:16:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tappal-rerscompetition2018/</guid><description>This year, we participated for the first time in CTL model checking competition RERS and we are happy to announce that we solved all problems proposed by the competition and rank as the most successful tool in this category (though there were no medals in this category as it was an experimental run this year). More details are available (here)[http://rers-challenge.org/2018/index.php?page=results].</description></item><item><title>10 Years Anniversary of TAPAAL</title><link>/news/10-years-of-tapaal/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 10:14:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/10-years-of-tapaal/</guid><description>Yesterday we celebrated 10 Years Anniversary of TAPAAL. It was great to meet 21 out of the total of 34 TAPAAL developers, some of them arriving also from USA.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.4.3 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.4.3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 15:10:43 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.4.3/</guid><description>We are glad to announce another update of TAPAAL 3.4.3 that
fixes a bug in the untimed engine for partial order reduction with inhibitor arcs, and
fixes a bug in the unfolding of colored Petri nets in the untimed engine.
This is a recommend update for all TAPAAL users.</description></item><item><title>Two Gold Medals and One Silver at MCC&#39;18</title><link>/news/mcc18-2-gold-medals/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 15:11:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/mcc18-2-gold-medals/</guid><description>We are very glad to announce that TAPAAL won a gold medal both in the reachability and CTL model checking category and a silver medal in upper bounds category at Model Checking Contest 2018 in Bratislava. More details can be found here https://mcc.lip6.fr/results.php.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.4.2 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.4.2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 15:22:49 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.4.2/</guid><description>We are glad to announce another update of TAPAAL 3.4.2 that
fixes issues with PNML and XML query export of nets,
fixes a net composition with constants on weighted arcs,
structural transition statistics now includes the rules A to I,
fixes an uncought exception when renaming transitions to an invalid name, and
is distributed with the untimed engine verifypn 3.0.0 contains a general performance improvement, adds support for colored nets verification (no GUI support yet) and fixes a number of bugs for nets with inhibitors arcs, arithmetic exppressions and other small issues.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.4.1 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.4.1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 13:56:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.4.1/</guid><description>We are glad to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.4.1 that fixes some bugs in the previous release, most notably it addresses the issues with
launching TAPAAL GUI on Mac Os X with Java 9, conversion of Reachability to CTL queires in the query creation dialog, fixes in evaluating arithmetical expressions and nested deadlock queries in the untimed verifypn engine for P/T nets. This is a highly recommended update to all TAPAAL users.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.4.0 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.4.0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 15:15:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.4.0/</guid><description>We are happy to announce the release of TAPAAL 3.4.0 with improved engines for the discrete-time verification (verifydtapn) and the untimed engine (verifypn). It also includes a GUI support for using partial order reduction for the discrete-time engine. The summary of features are:
Partial order reduction to the verifydtapn engine. Support for timed-safety-games to the engine (no GUI support yet). Refactoring of verifydtapn engine and all around for performance improvement (including new successor generator).</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.3.0 and Two Silver Medals at MCC&#39;17</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.3.0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 15:14:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.3.0/</guid><description>We are proud to announce that also at this year Model Checking Contest 2017, TAPAAL won a silver medal both in the reachability category and also in the CTL model checking category. We are very glad to release a new TAPAAL 3.3.0 version that now includes also the newest implementation of the verifypn (untimed) engine as well as a full GUI support and integration of the CTL engine. The main new features include:</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.2.1 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.2.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2016 15:14:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.2.1/</guid><description>TAPAAL Team Announce the Release of TAPAAL 3.2.1 that includes
several bug fixes in the GUI and improved performance of the untimed verifypn engine. We are not distributing 32 bit binaries for linux and mac anymore as we do not think they used. Should you miss them, let us know please.</description></item><item><title>Two Silver Medals for TAPAAL</title><link>/news/two-silver-medals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 15:15:58 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/two-silver-medals/</guid><description>In this year competition of Petri net tools our tool TAPAAL defended a silver medal in the reachability category and for the first time participated also in the CTL category where it received also a silver medal. More details can be found here.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.2.0 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.2.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 15:15:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.2.0/</guid><description>The TAPAAL Team announces the release of TAPAAL 3.2.0 that includes:
the possibility to hide/show place and transition names creation of shared places and transitions directly from the context menu improved simulator that allows to setup time delays using a slider a new memory compression technique (PTrie) in the engine for workflow analysis possibility to import XML queries for untimed nets from MCC-15 competition numerous bug fixes.</description></item><item><title>Silver Medal for TAPAAL Defended</title><link>/news/two-silver-melds-defended/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 15:08:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/two-silver-melds-defended/</guid><description>We are proud to announce that at this year&amp;rsquo;s annual model checking contest the model checker TAPAAL defended the silver medal in the category of reachability analysis of P/T nets, this time in competition also with tools that implement parallel state-space exploration, and it was the first tool in the subcategory of deadlock detection. The results were announced on June 23rd, 2015 at the Petri Net conference in Bruxelles. Details about the competition should become soon available at the competition web-page here.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.1.3 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.1.3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 13:13:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.1.3/</guid><description>TAPAAL Team Announce the Release of TAPAAL 3.1.3 that includes
bug fixes in the workflow analysis and query creating dialog, allows to execute 0 time unit delays in the simulator, and improves compatibility with the most recent UPPAAL verification engine.</description></item><item><title>Silver Medal for TAPAAL</title><link>/news/silver-medal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 15:10:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/silver-medal/</guid><description>We are happy to announce that TAPAAL won a silver medal at the annual Model Cheching Contest in Tunis this year (co-located with Petri Nets 2014) in the reachability cathegory and received a medal for a third place in the state-space generation cathegory.
Details can be found here.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.1.2 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.1.2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 15:14:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.1.2/</guid><description>TAPAAL Team Announce the Release of TAPAAL 3.1.2 that includes
bug fixes in the untimed and discrete verification engines small GUI improvements in the simulator fixes a bug in the query dialog that allowed to use darts in cases where it should be disabled improved export/import of traces in a new XML format.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.1.1 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.1.1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 08:11:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.1.1/</guid><description>TAPAAL team announces the release of 3.1.1 that inlcudes:
bug fixes in the untimed and discrete verification engines small bug fixes in the GUI PNML loading for nets with fractional x/y-coordinates overrride of queries in batch processing for deadlock check displays place-bound statistics for the discrete engine verifydtapn. A highly recommended upgrade to all TAPAAL users.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.1.0 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.1.0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2014 22:36:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.1.0/</guid><description>TAPAAL team announces the release of a majour upgrade 3.1.0 that inlcudes:
PNML import/export is now available within TAPAAL GUI. Over/under approximation of the intervals in the net. Optimized workflow engine, in particular for strong soundness check. New untimed structural reductions in verifyPN engine. Possibility to define general arithmetic queries over the number of tokens in places (in the manual edit mode). Fastes trace option added to the query dialog for the discrete-time engine.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.0.0 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-3.0.0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 20:40:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-3.0.0/</guid><description>The TAPAAL team is very happy to announce a major upgrade of TAPAAL. The new release of 3.0.0 includes numerous GUI improvements and bug fixes, together with the following selected new features.
GUI and verification support for timed workflow analysis (available under Tool/Workflow analysis) that allow to check for soundness and strong soundness of workflow nets and computing the shortest and longest execution times. A brand new dedicated verification engine verifypn that supports an efficient verification of untimed nets and allows for a quick linear over-approximation test even for timed nets.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.4.3 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.4.3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 20:47:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.4.3/</guid><description>We are happy to announce an update to our tool that fixes an issue for trace generation in the discrete TAPAAL engine for EG/AF queries and the Time Dart option.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.4.1 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.4.1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 15:20:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.4.1/</guid><description>We are very happy to introduce a new release of TAPAAL 2.4.1 that contains some bug fixes, namely:
a problem with loading verifyta.exe file (UPPAAL engine) on some windows installations running Java 6, a bug in simulator when used with urgent transitions, corrects the interpretation of verification results as some are actually valid also for the continuous semantics, and propertly terminates processes run via the batch processing dialog.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.4.0 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.4.0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 21:56:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.4.0/</guid><description>We are very happy to introduce a new release of TAPAAL 2.4.0 that
adds the possibility to model urgent transitions (enabled urgent transition disables time passing), adds deadlock as one of a possible propositions in the query dialog (a marking is a deadlock if after any delay no transition gets ever enabled), improves the simulator by adding a random automated simulator and allowing to export/import traces, fixes a number of bugs and contains some GUI improvements, and makes performance improvements in the discrete-time engine verifydtapn.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.3.0 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.3.0/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 15:23:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.3.0/</guid><description>We are very happy to introduce a new release of TAPAAL 2.3.0 that
supports Java 7 (and Java 6), has a considerably improved discrete verification engine verifydtapn 2.0 which includes semi-symbolic optimization called timed-darts and memory optimization option PTrie, has a brand new simulator that shows the currently enabled transitions (red ones) and future-enabled transitions (blue ones), supports native file open/save dialogs, contains numerous GUI improvements (constant highlight, deadlock information in trace simulation), and fixes a number of bugs.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 3.6.0 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.4.2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 15:14:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.4.2/</guid><description>We are very happy to introduce a new release of TAPAAL 2.4.2 that contains some bug fixes, namely:
explanation for verification results in batch processing and correction of PTrie and Dart options for the verifydtapn engine editor improvements for urgent transitions and shared places/transitions problem with UPPAAL translations for models with zero tokens and zero extra tokens deadlock reporting problem in simulator loading invalid XML files problem with removing orphan transitions that have inhibitor arcs &amp;ldquo;some trace&amp;rdquo; option is now remembered undo/redo of urgency flag fix for boundedness check with verifydtapn engine a few other bug fixes.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.2.1 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.2.1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2012 15:16:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.2.1/</guid><description>TAPAAL 2.2.1 is fixing a few bugs in the discrete verification engine of TAPAAL (verifydtapn), namely:
a memory leak, a problem with search termination for liveness properties, and a problem in computing successors for nets with weights The GUI has not been modified since 2.2.0.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.2.0 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.2.0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 15:20:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.2.0/</guid><description>TAPAAL 2.2.0 is a major upgrade of the tool featuring a new open source engine for closed timed-arc Petri nets. The main new features are:
new TAPAAL engine called verifydtapn for discrete verification of closed nets updated TAPAAL engine verifytapn transition statistics that shows how many times transitions were enabled during the search support for weighted arcs in the editor, simulator and the new engine fully adjustable workspace that can be saved in preferences new shortcuts, namely the arrows that can be used both in editor and simulator (e.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.1.3 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.1.3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 15:09:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.1.3/</guid><description>TAPAAL 2.1.3 is a maintenance release fixing some minor problems in the editor when multiple objects were selected and when deleting places. It also fixes a problem in a simulator where arrows used in the delay field affected also the current position in the trace.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.1.2 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.1.2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 15:15:17 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.1.2/</guid><description>TAPAAL 2.1.2 is a maintenance release fixing a few smaller bugs in the GUI as well as the interpretation of the verification answers for EG and AF queries. A recommended update for all TAPAAL users.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.1.1 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.1.1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 15:19:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.1.1/</guid><description>TAPAAL 2.1.1 is a maintenance release fixing several bugs and
improving the speed of loading large models and moving/sorting in the component list, introducing a new update notification dialog, fixing a rare memory leak in the TAPAAL engine verifytapn, possibility to change the values of constants using the arrows left/right, user preferences are now relative to the version of TAPAAL, tool tips can be disabled, query dialog allows to create any query and suggests automatically the most suitable verification engine, and it is now possible to move in the error trace using the arrows up/down while the arrows left/right change the currently displayed component.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.1.0 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.1.0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 15:21:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.1.0/</guid><description>TAPAAL 2.1.0 is a major release with several new features and GUI improvements. The main updates include:
A new version of TAPAAL engine that allows to use discrete inclusion technique even for queries that are now upward closed. Numerous GUI improvements including a fully resizable panels, possibility for different workspace configurations for showing/hiding the interval [0,inf), and more. During the verification process there is now displayed a timer. Simulator now displays a clickable list of enabled transitions in all active components.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.0.2 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.0.2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 15:13:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.0.2/</guid><description>We are announcing the release of the following TAPAAL updates:
TAPAAL 2.0.2 TAPAAL 2.0.2 is a maintenance release that fixes a number of bugs, one of them connected to slow verification in case of the presence of orphan transitions (no input and no output arcs) and it fixes some rare issues during the saving of a net. The release also improves the layout of the query dialog and several other dialogs and a new example of train level crossing has been added to File/Example net.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.0.1 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.0.1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 15:12:08 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.0.1/</guid><description>We are announcing the release of the following TAPAAL updates:
TAPAAL 2.0.1 TAPAAL 2.0.1 is a maintenance release with a number of bug fixes, one of them connected to a wrong boundedness checking result in some particular scenarios. This is a highly recommended update for all users of 2.0.0.
Note also that new TAPAAL exercises were added to the Documentation page.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 2.0.0 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-2.0.0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2011 15:18:03 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-2.0.0/</guid><description>We are announcing the release of the following TAPAAL updates:
TAPAAL 2.0.0 TAPAAL 2.0 is a major release with many completely new features and in particular TAPAAL&amp;rsquo;s own verification engine that is now distributed together with TAPAAL.
The main new features are:
TAPAAL engine (both 32 and 64 bit version) with symmetry reduction, concrete trace generation, discrete inclusion, heuristic search Component-based design editor with shared places and transitions Flexible batch processing dialog Numerous GUI improvements (view/hide of panels, updated query editor, improved verification statistics, &amp;hellip;) For details about the release, look on detailed changelog on launchpad.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 1.4.3 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-1.4.3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 15:20:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-1.4.3/</guid><description>The TAPAAL Core Team announces versions 1.4.3 of TAPAAL. We are announcing the release of the following TAPAAL updates:
TAPAAL 1.4.3 This is a maintenance release and contain only bugfixes. It fixes an number of bugs
For details about the release, look on detailed changelog on launchpad.
https://launchpad.net/tapaal/1.4/1.4.3
Download:
http://www.tapaal.net/download</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 1.4.2 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-1.4.2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 15:12:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-1.4.2/</guid><description>The TAPAAL Core Team announces versions 1.4.2 of TAPAAL. We are announcing the release of the following TAPAAL updates:
TAPAAL 1.4.2 This is a maintenance release and contain only bugfixes. It fixes an important bug concerning boundness checking.
For details about the release, look on detailed changelog on launchpad.
https://launchpad.net/tapaal/1.4/1.4.2
Download:
http://www.tapaal.net/download</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 1.4.1 Released</title><link>/news/tapaal-1.4.1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 15:12:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-1.4.1/</guid><description>The TAPAAL Core Team announces versions 1.4.1 of TAPAAL. We are announcing the release of the following TAPAAL updates:
TAPAAL 1.4.1 This is a maintenance release and contain only bugfixes. It fixes bugs introduced in the 1.4 release.
For details about the release, look on detailed changelog on launchpad.
https://launchpad.net/tapaal/1.4/1.4.1
Download:
http://www.tapaal.net/?id=25</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 1.4</title><link>/news/tapaal-1.4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 15:13:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-1.4/</guid><description>We are happy to announce a new release of TAPAAL 1.4 that adds new features like
timed inhibitor arcs, completely new query creation dialog, option to model and verify untimed Petri nets (mainly for educational purposes), several visual improvements, bug fixes and it deals with the new licensing policy of UPPAAL. The release also contains an improved example of Alternating Bit Protocol that shows the power of transport arcs that allow to time-stamp tokens travelling in the net.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 1.3</title><link>/news/tapaal-1.3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2009 15:14:44 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-1.3/</guid><description>We are happy to announce a new release of TAPAAL 1.3.
This release fixes a number of bugs and brings several new features like:
parametrized net templates with constants optimization of the number of extra tokens in case the net is bounded export of nets directly to tikz improved layout of the list of queries automatic update notifier</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 1.2</title><link>/news/tapaal-1.2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 16:36:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-1.2/</guid><description>A new release of TAPAAL 1.2 is now available at the download page.
This release fixes a number of bugs discovered since the last release and it includes now several demo nets that are accessible directly from the file menu under example nets.</description></item><item><title>TAPAAL 1.1</title><link>/news/tapaal-1.1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2009 16:37:02 +0100</pubDate><guid>/news/tapaal-1.1/</guid><description>A new release of TAPAAL 1.1 is now available at the download page.
This release fixes a number of bugs and introduces two new features:
boundedness checking and visualization of untimed traces for the verification of liveness properties. Finally, a few demo examples are now included in the distribution. In particular, new users might want to open and experiment with the self-explanatory example intro-example.xml.</description></item></channel></rss>